<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-08-01T05:44:34-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Faculty</title><subtitle>unleash our faculties
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Traceability Matters</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/profile/traceability-matters/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Traceability Matters" /><published>2017-07-04T22:29:53-05:00</published><updated>2017-07-04T22:29:53-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/profile/traceability-matters</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/profile/traceability-matters/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;Traceability attempts to track small bits of the commercial food industry and demonstrate how challenging it is to be informed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DePaul University alumn, Brooke Kravitz, made good use of her senior thesis project by focusing on a topic that touches the lives of millions of people every day.  The topic is food traceability. It’s incredibly important for U.S. consumers to be able to access the origin of the food which they are consuming. Commercial food industries ought not to fear providing consumers with the facts and sources of their products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brooke Kravitz combines experimental illustrations, captivating imagery, and an overall inviting aesthetic that makes a complex topic worth exploring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wideimage&quot; src=&quot;/../images/post-traceability-1.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figcaption&gt;

It’s almost impossible for the average U.S. consumer to have complete control over their food. Commercial growing, harvesting, processing, and distribution are highly complex operations mostly hidden away from the public. Through posters, animation, and booklets, Traceability attempts to track small bits of the commercial food industry and demonstrate how challenging it is to be informed. Food traceability is a crucial factor in other issues like nutrition, human and animal welfare, and sustainability. It’s time that the industry went opensource, making information more visible and operations more transparent. Bon appétit!


– Brooke Kravitz, on Traceability

&lt;/figcaption&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Traceability attempts to track small bits of the commercial food industry and demonstrate how challenging it is to be informed.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/post-traceability.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Goodbye, Leonard Cohen</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tribute/goodbye-leonard-cohen/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Goodbye, Leonard Cohen" /><published>2016-11-11T21:29:53-06:00</published><updated>2016-11-11T21:29:53-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tribute/goodbye-leonard-cohen</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tribute/goodbye-leonard-cohen/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;Singer-Songwriter Leonard Cohen passed away on November 10th, 2016, at the age of 82.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cohen was born in Canada in 1934 and is known for his emotional and honest writing and songs that explored and exposed the human experience. Through his music that spanned numerous decades, Cohen brilliantly provided solace to his listeners. Cohen’s music pierced through the boundaries of depression, despair, love, loneliness, religion, loss, and more. Cohen’s art, life, and dedication to his craft, leaves us with a lifetime of  alleviation. We love you, Leonard Cohen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/vbjRTN3-jCg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;figcaption&gt;Leaving the Table from Leonard Cohen’s latest album, You Want it Darker (2016).&lt;/figcaption&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Singer-Songwriter Leonard Cohen passed away on November 10th, 2016, at the age of 82.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/post-good-bye-leonard-cohen.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">On Quality</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/writing/on-quality/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Quality" /><published>2016-07-04T07:29:53-05:00</published><updated>2016-07-04T07:29:53-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/writing/on-quality</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/writing/on-quality/">&lt;p&gt;Quality is often a personal definition that depends on the observer, creator, consumer, producer—the list goes on. As we evolve and develop, our views on quality shift due to our continued existence. Quality can be described as a collection of influences and experiences that determine what is held responsible for the differentiation between good and bad. The passing of time allows an accumulation of influences to combine and select individual qualities to gravitate toward. Interactions with products, services, and experiences provide an opportunity for our subconscious criteria to come forth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;Quality should extend the senses and provide alternative methods that amplify our existence.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As creators and producers of public work, there’s an amount of vulnerability that is placed upon work that exits the workplace and enters the arena of public consumption. The quality which is placed upon a particular artifact derives from its process, aesthetic, voice, rhetoric, space, and intention. The responsibility is immense and shouldn’t be one to take lightly—our choices and decisions can destroy or inspire. By designing for temporal desires, value is minimized and thus contributing to a downward spiral of illusions, tricks, and forgery. This forgery has the potential to provide comfort under certain conditions that can be destructive or serve as a short-term relief or distraction.
&lt;img class=&quot;leftimage&quot; src=&quot;/../images/post-on-quality-this-or-that.jpg&quot; /&gt;
Quality is able to acquire invisibility when it coexists with the everyday and acts under the radar. Bad quality is more often criticized and noticed because it stunts our senses into coming to realization that something is wrong—like an infection, our body rejects any foreign confrontation that contradicts our stance. However, bad quality also possesses the ability to numb our senses into accepting that which fails to inspire. Overtime, this bad quality can go undetected and eventually become socially accepted. Quality should extend the senses and provide alternative methods that amplify our existence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Living in a digital space where endless amounts of content is shared throughout various social networks and mobile applications, the definition of quality is defined by others and is dependent on popularity rather than value. A plethora of posts beg for our approval and social media networks claim to know our needs. Only when we turn to these sources for alleviation and comfort, do we provide a stamp of approval upon their so called caring and personal content that cares so much about our well-being. Rather than nourishing, they feed our cravings that only provide a lack of sustainability. There are countless avenues of communication which are used by millions of people worldwide, such as Facebook, Snapchat, Instagram, and Twitter—yet they present only self-interest in gaining power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quality is able to be approached and judged from a political perspective as well as a creative one. The political perspective is focused on private matters excluded from the public. Factors weigh in that create smoky mirrors with false personas. Our rejection is the only way to combat toxic forces that aim to define and devaluate human values. The creative perspective inhibits a human approach. Quality exists beyond form and should only ever tell the truth. Without the truth, quality can’t exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, as creators we can safely say that we all encompass an individual style and philosophy that we attain to when developing and exploring ideas. It varies from person to person which don’t necessarily have to encompass all the same views but at least should carry a human-driven purpose intended to provide positive outcomes that create harmony within our shared existence. Through combinations of design elements, historical references, influences, and culture—we create solutions that we believe are the outcomes to the final phase of our work. We make choices with the hope that it couldn’t have been done any other way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind that quality does not only exist in visible ways that we encounter but quality also exists hidden under layers of work that can remain invisible and foreign to us, it exists in chemistry, economics, linguistics, engineering, etc. All fields carry depths of design that even in fields out of our scope, can still connect with us and when it does,  it should enlighten and not hinder growth.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Christian Solorzano</name></author><summary type="html">Quality is often a personal definition that depends on the observer, creator, consumer, producer—the list goes on. As we evolve and develop, our views on quality shift due to our continued existence. Quality can be described as a collection of influences and experiences that determine what is held responsible for the differentiation between good and bad. The passing of time allows an accumulation of influences to combine and select individual qualities to gravitate toward. Interactions with products, services, and experiences provide an opportunity for our subconscious criteria to come forth.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/post-on-quality-cover.jpg" /></entry></feed>